that criminalize homeless existence. Who here knows that in many cities across the United States it is now illegal to sit on the sidewalk, to wrap oneself in a blanket, to sleep in your own car, to offer food to a stranger? I know about these laws because I've watched as friends and other travelers were hauled off to jail or received citations for committing these so-called crimes. Many of you might be wondering why anyone would choose a life like this, under the thumb of discriminatory laws, eating out of trash cans, sleeping under bridges, picking up seasonal jobs here and there. The answer to such a question is as varied as the people that take to the road, but travelers often respond with a single word: freedom. Until we live in a society where every human is assured dignity in their labor so that they can work to live well, not only work to survive, there will always be an element of those who seek the open road as a means of escape, of liberation and, of course, of rebellion. Thank you. (Applause)
que criminaliza la existencia nómada. ¿Sabían que en muchas ciudades de Estados Unidos es ilegal sentarse en la acera, taparse con una cobija, dormir en el coche, u ofrecerle comida a un extraño? Conozco estas leyes porque he visto como multan y encarcelan a mis amigos y a otros viajeros por cometer estos supuestos crímenes. Muchos de Uds. se preguntan por qué alguien querría vivir así, oprimidos por leyes discriminatorias, comiendo de la basura, durmiendo bajo puentes, y trabajando de vez en cuando. La respuesta es tan diversa como la misma comunidad de viajeros, pero ellos siempre responden con una sola palabra: "libertad". A menos de que la sociedad se asegure de que cada persona pueda tener un trabajo digno para poder vivir bien, no solo sobrevivir, siempre existirán aquellos que verán las calles como un medio de escape, de liberación y de rebelión. Gracias. (Aplausos)